在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
虎子们回来了
The Cons are back
飞过山处境非常危险
Cliff might be knee deep in scrap.
飞过山的生命信号…刚刚消失了
Cliffjumper's life signal... just went offline.
时至今日 地球上只剩下我们五个汽车人了
As of today, only we five Autobots remain on this earth.
他们是什么？
What are they?
会说话的车变的机器人
Talking cars that turn into robots
或者机器人变的车
or the other way around.
听着 你可能有危险
Look, you maybe in danger
因为你看到了我们
because you are one of the few
很少有人知道我们的存在
one of the only who have ever seen us.
你们为什么来地球？
Why are you here?
保护你们的星球免受威震天的侵害
To protect your planet from Megatron.
但如果他即将东山再起
But if his return is imminent
又要掀起一场腥风血雨
it could be catastrophic.
我回来了！
I have returned!
威震天陛下 您不在之时 我们发现了数个能量矿
Of the energon deposits we have located while you're away, Lord Megatron
而这个矿的储备简直是取之不竭
this one is by far the most significant.
这段时间 机械兵一直在不停地采矿
The drones have been mining without a pause during your absence
库存量尤为可观
and have amassed quite a stock pile.
来人啊 给我拿个样本！
You there, fetch me a sample.
红蜘蛛！
Starscream.
既然我已经回来了
Now that I have returned
就该由我发号施令
I will issue the commands.
我…明白 威震天陛下
I… understand, Lord Megatron.
作为您的忠实奴仆
Then as your humble servant
我随时准备启动太空桥
shall I ready the Space Bridge
迎接这三年来 您在太空组建的霸天虎军队
to bring forth the Decepticon army you have surely gathered during your three years in space?
我的军队会来的
My army will come.
但我在太空漂流时
But my time away has yielded a more...
找到一种能够增强实力的神秘方法
intriguing means of materializing them
这种物质的液体形态
the solidified form of the matter the ancient techs refer to
在古代资料中被称为――宇宙大帝之血
as the blood of the Unicron.
“毁灭者”宇宙大帝
Unicron the Destroyer.
但据说他的血液跟火种不兼容
But it is said that his blood is the anti-spark.
“采于宇宙之滨 将得黑暗能量”！
Plucked from cosmic shores, gaze upon Dark Energon.
传说它威力无比 甚至能…起死回生
Legend tells that it holds the power to... revive the dead.
我们需要找具尸体来试试看
We require only cadaver to be certain.
你愿意做出巨大牺牲吗？
Are you willing to make the ultimate sacrifice?
这个我看没必要
That may not be necessary.
请允许我 威震天陛下
If I may, Lord Megatron.
就当是为您的回归献上的贺礼
Consider it a welcome-home present.
既然你们发现了我们
And since you now know of our existence
照昨晚的事情来看
I fear that as of the last night
恐怕霸天虎是不会放过你们的
the Decepticons know of yours.
明白 如果看到任何不明车辆 立刻报警
Got it, if we spot any strange vehicles, call 911.
我们可以走了吗？
Can we go now?
你疯了吗？
Are you insane?
这儿对我来说就像天堂一样
I'm living a dream here in Botswana
你们谁都别想破坏我的美梦！
and I will now allow you or anyone else to shatter it.
你们三个最好接受我们的监护
It is best that you three remain under our watch.
起码我们要弄清楚 敌人有什么意图
At least until we can determine our enemy's intentions.
擎天柱 恕我直言
Optimus, with all due respect
无论在这里还是别处 这些孩子都同样危险
the human children are in as much danger here as anywhere.
小孩子？
Children?
他们没有防护罩！
They have no protective shell!
如果不小心被踩到 他们就…扁了
If they get underfoot, they will go… squish.
那么从现在起 救护车
Then for the time being, Ratchet
我们必须走一步 看一步
we must watch where we step.
那是什么？
What's that?
近程传感器
Proximity sensor.
有人在上面
Someone's up top.
是福勒探员
It's Agent Fowler.
我们不是唯一知道你们的人类吗？
I thought we were the only humans who know about you guys.
特派员福勒是我们和外界之间的特别联络人
Special Agent Fowler is our designated liaison to the outside world.
他来找我们 一定有要事发生
As he tends to visit only when there're issues.
你们最好暂时先别和他见面
It maybe best if you did not meet him at this time.
七辆车被毁 三十四起剐蹭事故
Seven wrecks, thirty-four fender benders
三小时交通堵塞
a three hour traffic jam
还有一条特别消息
and a particular note:
多家媒体报道 发现一辆不明车型的高速摩托
numerous reports of a speeding motorcycle of unknown make
和一辆黄黑条纹的肌肉车
and a black & yellow custom muscle car.
那么 你有什么心里话要说吗 擎天柱？
So, anything you care to get off your tin chest, Prime?
情况尚在我们控制之下 福勒探员
We have the situation under control, Agent Fowler.
他们回来了 是吧？
They're back, aren't they?
如果你指的是霸天虎
If you're referring to the Decepticons
我怀疑他们从未离开过
I have doubts that they ever left.
你们的星球太有开发价值了
Your planet is much too valuable.
那我现在就要通知五角大楼
Then it's time to wake up the Pentagon.
听我说 福勒探员
Hear me, Agent Fowler.
如果和霸天虎对抗
We're your best
我们也许是你们唯一可以依靠的力量
possibly your only defence against the Decepticon threat.
别太自负
Says you.
嘿 肉条
Hey, fleshy.
有人血溅高速公路吗？
Did anyone get spattered on that freeway?
领袖卫队知道什么时候该用武力
Team Prime knows when to use force
出手的轻重我们心中有数
and how much to use.
隔板 那个我还有用呐！
Bulkhead, I needed that!
够了！
Enough!
军队的干涉只会导致更大的灾难
Military involvement will only result in catastrophe.
或许你可以接受人类尸横遍野 福勒探员
Perhaps you can condone wide spread human casualties, Agent Fowler.
但我 决不能接受
I, however, cannot.
那就为我们双方的利益着想 擎天柱
Then do us both a favour and handle this, Prime
做得…干净点儿
under the radar.
要么让我来
Or I will.
不自量力
Pretty big bearings…
区区一个人类而已
for a human.
福勒探员担心的是他的世界 隔板
Agent Fowler has concerns for his world, Bulkhead
这是他的职责
as he should be.
看看源自黑暗的力量
Let us see if power born of darkness
能否重燃火种
can reignite the spark.
那就是你的计划？！
That's your plan?
复活死掉的汽车人 让我们挨揍？
Bring Autobots back from the dead to attack us?
那已经不再是个汽车人了
That is no longer an Autobot.
只是个没有意识的猛兽
Just a mindless beast
它唯一的本能就是 摧毁挡在路上的一切
it's only instinct to destroy anything in its path.
看吧 红蜘蛛
There, Starscream
我无坚不摧的军队已经上路 这终极武器…
rise the indestructible seed of my army, the ultimate weapon…
一旦被我掌握 将会大发神威
once I learn to control it.
该死的地球科技！
Blast that earth tech!
飞过山的信号又出现了
Cliffjumper's signal pop back online.
飞过山是谁？
Who's Cliffjumper?
怎么可能？
How is that possible?
当然不可能
It isn't.
又出故障了
Another bug.
系统故障一大堆
The system is chock-full of them.
飞过山有没有可能还活着？
If there's any chance Cliff's alive?
救护车 准备医务室
Ratchet, prepare sick bay.
可能用得上
We may need it.
我们能做点什么？
what can we do?
和救护车留守
Remain with Ratchet.
汽车人 出发！
Autobots, roll out!
刚才是怎么回事？
What just happened?
我用环陆桥把他们送到了特定的坐标地点
I transported them to the designated coordinates via the Ground Bridge.
环陆桥是什么？
What's a Ground Bridge?
太空桥技术的简化版而已
Oh... A scale-down version of Space Bridge technology.
因为我们现在没有星际旅行需要的设备和能量
Since we don't currently possess the means or the energon required for inter-galactic travel.
你们被困在…
You're stuck here…
地球上了？
on earth?
和你们困在一起 是的
With the likes of you, yes.
但我建造了环陆桥
But I constructed the Ground Bridge
可以到达你们星球的任何角落
to enable travel from here to anywhere on your planet.
人类能用吗？
Whoa, does it work for humans?
当然能
Naturally.
你是说
You mean I could just
我这么一跳 就能到东京去看我的父母吗？
shoot on over and visit my parents in Tokyo?
眨眼工夫
Within moments.
这样吧 我马上把你们三个都送过去
In fact, allow me to send you there immediately, all three of you.
说话当心 救护车
Watch it, Ratchet.
能量矿
Energon mine.
照这个规模来看
Judging by its scale
霸天虎应该已经开采过一段时间了
the Decepticons have been tunneling here for quite some time.
我们去找飞过山！
Let's find Cliffjumper.
这是什么玩意儿？
What is this, anyway?
坏了 别碰
Broken, don't touch.
那个也别碰
Don't touch that either.
有什么东西是我们可以碰的吗？
So is there anything we can touch?
你们干嘛要用人类的计算机？
How come you guys are using human computers?
我们别无选择
It certainly isn't by choice.
我们当时接管了这个导弹发射井
It was handed down from the previous talents
这是那些天才留下的
when we inherited this former missile silo.
我根据需要做了一些调整
I made modifications as I see fit.
我想我能把故障修好
I think I can fix that.
真的吗？
Really?
这是超级复杂的科技 知不知道？
You know this is complex technology, don't you?
这可不是儿童玩具！
I mean it isn't a child's toy.
现在试试
Now try.
全速冲击！
Maximum overdrive!
全不费功夫
What an operation.
宇宙大帝之血
Blood of Unicron.
我如何才能揭开你的奥秘
How might I fathom the depth of your mystery
并得以支配你那惊人的力量？
become worthy of wielding your astonishing power.
威震天陛下 矿场出现入侵者
Lord Megatron, intruders have been detected in the mines.
擎天柱？
Optimus?
就是他
Indeed.
我还需要时间
I need more time to prepare on appropriate reception for my old friend.
为老朋友准备一个体面的欢迎仪式
启动飞船 准备撤离
Ready the ship for departure.
可我挖到的那些能量
But the energon I've mined...
会被汽车人抢走的！
the Autobots will sieze it!
那就把矿炸掉！
Then blow the mines!
是飞过山 我看到了
It's Cliff. I have a visual.
我们掩护你 上吧！
We'll cover you, go!
飞过山！
Cliff!
我们回家吧 搭档！
Let's get you home, partner!
擎天柱！
Prime!
我也想留下 但我有点洁癖
I'd stick around, but I'm squeamish.
要爆炸了！
The drone is gonna blow!
汽车人 出发！
Autobots, roll out!
救护车 把我们传送回去
Ratchet, bridge us back.
使用目的地坐标
Use the arrival coordinates
快！
now!
千钧一发啊
Cutting it a little bit close.
飞过山怎么样了？
How about Cliffjumper?
那爆炸是怎么回事？
What was that explosion?
你们打架了吗？
Was there a fight?
下次我们能去吗？
Can we come with next time?
听着！
Look!
嘿 嘿 神子
Hey, hey, Miko.
我们去看看 他们的抽屉里有什么宝贝
Let's go see what the bots hide in their sock drawers.
真的假的？
Seriously?
阿尔茜 你看到什么了？
Arcee, what did you see?
不是飞过山
Not Cliff.
起码…现在不是了
At least... not anymore.
他被改变了 被分尸
He was mutated, butchered
像大战时虎子做的试验那样
like something from those Con experiments during the war.
我没事 只是有点晕
I'm fine, just dizzy.
机器人也会头晕？
Robots who get dizzy?
机器人也会难过？
Robots with emotions?
机器人也会死？
Robots... who can die?
这是什么？
What is this?
不知道
Don't know.
飞过山浑身上下都是
Cliff was covered in it
还流了出来
leaking it.
马上去洗个净化澡 快
Go take a decontamination bath, now.
擎天柱  我不想打扰你 但…这儿没信号
Optimus, I hate to bug, but... no bars.
这是安全措施
A security precaution.
发射井的墙壁阻断了所有无线电波
The silo walls isolate all radio waves.
如果我现在不打电话给我妈妈
Well, if I don't call my mom like now
我敢肯定 警察会开始找我的
I'm pretty sure the cops will be out looking for me.
你犯过法吗？
Have you broken the law?
噢 是宵禁
Oh, curfew
已经晚上十点多了
it's after 10pm.
我也该回家了
I'd better get home, too
否则我一年都别想出门
or I'll be grounded for a year.
地球风俗
Earth customs
是我考虑不周
I hadn't considered.
但还是要保证你们的安全
But the issue of your safety remains.
隔板 送神子回家
Bulkhead, accompany Miko home.
太棒了！吓死我的监护人！
Awesome! My host parents will freak!
保持伪装形态进行监视
And maintain covert surveillance in vehicle form.
在路边望风 明白
Curbside duty, got it.
大黄蜂 你来照顾拉夫
Bumblebee, you'll watch over Raf.
救护车…
Ratchet...
忙着呢！
Busy!
阿尔茜 你护送杰克
Arcee, you'll accompany Jack.
噢 我还是晕
Oh, still dizzy.
医生说你没事了
You're fine, says your physician.
阿尔茜 我只想说
Arcee, I just wanted to say
对于你的损失 我真的很遗憾
I'm really sorry for your loss.
你能理解什么叫损失吗？
What could you possibly know about loss?
怎么？你以为只有你才有心事吗？
What? You think you're the only one with problems?
泡妞失败算什么心事！
I'm not sure girl-trouble counts!
我敢说 我泡妞失败 正因为那晚碰见了你
I'm pretty sure my girl-trouble started the night I met you.
虎子！
Cons!
不！是我妈
No! Mom.
杰克？
Jack?
妈妈！别激动 我可以解释
Mom! Don't freak, I can explain.
你能吗？
Can you?
杰克逊・达比 我们已经谈过这个了
Jackson Darby, we've talked about this.
我知道 那个…
I know, and...
你不懂
You don't know.
你不知道 你不在家时 我已经够担心了
I worred about you enough when you were not here.
我现在还要担心你骑摩托出事吗？
Now I have to worry about you driving a motorcycle?
我已经十六岁了
I'm sixteen.
不可能永远骑十变速自行车
I can't be riding a ten speed forever.
你哪来的钱买这个？
How did you even afford this?
是二手货
It's used.
挺破的 真的
It's abused, really
需要大修
needs a ton of repairs.
但其实…
But the point is...
买头盔的时候 我还是小孩
I may have been a kid when I bought this
但我已经长大了
but I'm not anymore.
你经常教育我 做选择要负责任
You always tell me to make responsible choices.
现在 我选择了她
Well, I chose her.
我会负责的
And I'll be responsible.
我发誓
I promise.
“她”？
"Her"?
我觉得你还不能把女孩子带回家过夜
I don't think you could be bringing girls home just yet.
我…觉得是她带我回来的
I'd... like to think she brought me.
好吧 很高兴你终于有理由戴头盔了
Well, I'm glad you finally have a reason to wear your helmet
每次骑车都要戴！
every single time you ride.
你得先跟我打招呼才行
You... will take me for a spin every once in a while?
看情况吧
We'll see.
她的脾气不太好
She's kind a temperamental.
嘘 你疯了吗？
Shhh, are you crazy?
会吵醒我妈妈的！
You'll wake up my mom!
去拿头盔 是时候上路了
Grab your helmet, it's go time.
今天是星期六啊！
Oh... It's Saturday!
你可以在基地陪大黄蜂看动画片
You can watch cartoons back at base with Bumblebee.
动画片…我都十六岁了
Cartoons? I'm sixteen.
留个纸条给你妈妈 不然她会担心的
And leave a note for your mom. She worries.
我看您不必再担心汽车人的骚扰了 主人
I don't think you need to worry further Autobot interference, master.
擎天柱已经完蛋了
Not with Optimus gone.
你说这话有什么证据吗？
And what evidence do you possess of this fact?
我炸掉了矿场
I destroyed the mines
按您的指示
as you instructed.
消灭擎天柱没那么容易
Optimus is not so easily destroyed.
我们之间千万年的战斗就可以证明
We have millennia worth of battles behind this to prove it.
或许您该休整一下 陛下
Maybe you should take a break, my Lord.
我担心 过度和黑暗能量接触
I worry that too much contact with the Dark Energon
会对您产生某种…负面影响
might allow its properties to adversely affect you.
其实 红蜘蛛
Or perhaps, Starscream
我可能还没接触够呢！
I have not permitted myself contact enough!
等等！威震天陛下 不！
Wait! Lord Megatron, no!
别拿您的火种室冒险！
Not your spark chamber!
您不知道会有什么后果！
You do not know what it will do!
这种粘液的基本元素 我从没见过
The base elements of this goo are like nothing I've ever encountered.
阿尔茜的症状发展迅速
It must be extremely concentrated
说明它一定是高度浓缩的
to have affected Arcee so rapidly.
可惜
Unfortunately
缺少合适的诊断工具
complete results are slow coming
完整分析慢得要死
without the use of proper diagnostic tools.
全都怪你 隔板！
Thank you very much, Bulkhead!